Guide to the First Million for Stanford Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
First million for Stanford collection
1921-1945
1921-1927
SC0452
Wilbur, Ray Lyman Jr.
1.25 Linear feet
This collection pertains to the fund-raising efforts launched in 1922 to raise $3 million for the Stanford University endowment fund. Included are correspondence, largely of Ray Lyman Wilbur, reports, alumni lists, subscription lists, a campaign manual, and clippings. There is one item that concerns University fund-raising from 1945.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1972.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
This collection pertains to the fund-raising efforts began in 1922 to raise $3 million for the Stanford University endowement fund. Included in the collection are correspondence, reports, alumni lists, subscription lists, a campaign manual, and the clippings. The correspondence is largely to and from Ray Lyman Wilbur. There is one item that pertains to University fund-raising from 1945.
Access Terms
Wilbur, Ray L., (Ray Lyman), 1875-1949; Universities and colleges--Finance.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Correspondence, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Form letters, instructions, lists, etc., 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Third Million - subscription reports, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Publicity and cultivation program (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Campaign manual ("Second Million") (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Medical Million - reports and rosters (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Returns from Pasadena and Los Angeles, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General committee list, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lists (various) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - District No. 1 list of workers (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Memoranda, 1921-22, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Student returns (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Responses to Wilbur's 3/18/26 letter, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Third million campaign (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Endowment Fund subscriptions (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Endowment Fund subscriptions (marked "pledges") (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Report on student body pledges (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Master list (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Third million - team reports, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Third million - major report, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Alumni lists (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Alumni lists (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Alumni lists (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Alumni lists (mixed cities) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - First million chairmen (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - District No. 2 (San Francisco) - major report, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Alameda County - major report, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - San Francisco - team lists (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Palo Alto - report, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Missouri - report, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Medical million, correspondence and reports, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Geographical and class breakdown, 1922-1924 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Preliminary working draft [of gift procurement program], 1945 May 15 (Box 3, Folder 9)